Daniel C. Dennett Papers MS138
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Daniel C. Dennett Papers
1958 -- 2022
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Dennett, Daniel C.
MS138
73.3 Linear Feet
483 Digital Object(s)
This collection contains the writings, correspondence, and curriculum vitae of Daniel C. Dennett. Writings consist of articles, book chapters, books, reviews, and commentaries.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list. This collection may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred by Daniel Dennett and staff, 2007 -- 2022.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in seven series: Writings; Unprocessed accessions; Correspondence; 2018 accessions; Curriculum vitae; 2020 accessions; and 2022 accessions.
Biographical / Historical
Daniel C. Dennett (1942- ) is University Professor and Austin B. Fletcher Professor of Philosophy, and Co-Director of the Center for Cognitive Studies at Tufts University. He was born in Boston, the son of a historian by the same name, and received his B.A. in philosophy from Harvard in 1963. He then went to Oxford to work with Gilbert Ryle, under whose supervision he completed his D.Phil. in philosophy in 1965. He taught at U.C. Irvine from 1965 to 1971, when he moved to Tufts, where he has taught ever since, aside from periods visiting at Harvard, Pittsburgh, Oxford, the École Normale Supérieure in Paris, the London School of Economics and the American University of Beirut.
His first book, Content and Consciousness, was published in 1969, followed by Brainstorms (1978), Elbow Room (1984), The Intentional Stance (1987), Consciousness Explained (1991), Darwin's Dangerous Idea (1995), Kinds of Minds (1996), and Brainchildren: A Collection of Essays 1984-1996 (1998), and Sweet Dreams: Philosophical Obstacles to a Science of Consciousness (2005). He is the author of over four hundred scholarly articles on various aspects on the mind. He has received two Guggenheim Fellowships, a Fulbright Fellowship, and a Fellowship at the Center for Advanced Studies in Behavioral Science. He was elected to the American Academy of Arts and Sciences in 1987.
Dennett was the Co-founder (in 1985) and Co-director of the Curricular Software Studio at Tufts, and has helped to design museum exhibits on computers for the Smithsonian Institution, the Museum of Science in Boston, and the Computer Museum in Boston.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains the writings, correspondence, and curriculum vitae of Daniel C. Dennett. Writings consist of articles, book chapters, books, reviews, and commentaries.
Faculty papers; Philosophy
- Writings, 1958 -- 2015; MS138.001; 4.15 Linear Feet; 415 Digital Object(s)
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains articles, book chapters, books, reviews, and commentaries by Daniel C. Dennett.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Quine and Ordinary Language, 1963; MS138.001.001.00001; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - The Mind and the Brain: Introspective Description in the Light of Neurological Findings; Intentionality, 1965; MS138.001.001.00002; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - The Analysis of Mind, 1967; MS138.001.001.00003; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - Machine Traces and Protocol Statements, 1968; MS138.001.001.00004; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    Artificial intelligence; Introspection; Functionalism
  - Geach on Intentional Identity, 1968-05-31; MS138.001.001.00005; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    Intentionality; Geach, P. T. (Peter Thomas), 1916-2013
  - Features of Intentional Action, 1968; MS138.001.001.00006; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - Content and Consciousness, 1969; MS138.001.001.00007; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - Content and Consciousness, 1969; MS138.001.001.00007.00001; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
      Dennett, Daniel C. Content and Conciousness. MSS, 1969. p. 1-138.
    - Content and Consciousness, 1969; MS138.001.001.00007.00002; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
      Dennett, Daniel C. Content and Conciousness. MSS, 1969. p. 139-310.
  - Status of the Mental: Review of Content and Consciousness, by Daniel C. Dennett, 1970; MS138.001.001.00008; Hamlyn, D. W. (Box 1)
  - Intentional Systems, 1971 -- 1995; MS138.001.001.00009; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - Intentional Systems, 1971-02-25; MS138.001.001.00009.00001; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
      Intentionality; Intentional stance
    - Intentionale Systeme [German translation of Intentional Systems], 1981; MS138.001.001.00009.00002; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    - Systemes Intentionnels [French translation of Intentional Systems, with new postscript], 1984; MS138.001.001.00009.00003; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    - Sistemas Intencionales [Spanish translation of Intentional Systems], 1985; MS138.001.001.00009.00004; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    - Intentional Systems, 1995; MS138.001.001.00009.00005; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - Review of the Subject of Consciousness, by C. O. Evans, 1971; MS138.001.001.00010; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    Made available by permission of Oxford Journals.
  - Review of Freedom of the Will, by J. R. Lucas, 1972-09-21; MS138.001.001.00011; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    Free will and determinism; Mechanistic determination; Gödel, Kurt; Lucas, J. R. (John Randolph), 1929-
  - Mechanism and Responsibility, 1973 -- 1985; MS138.001.001.00012; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - Mechanism and Responsibility, 1973; MS138.001.001.00012.00001; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    - Mecanicismo y Responsabilidad [Spanish translation of Mechanism and Responsibility], 1985; MS138.001.001.00012.00002; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - Comment on Wilfrid Sellars, 1974; MS138.001.001.00013; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    Functionalism; Intentional explanation; Meaning (philosophy); Intentional stance; Sellars, Wilfrid
  - Das Philosophisches Wörterbuch [early German edition of the Philosophical Lexicon], 1974; MS138.001.001.00014; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - Why the Law of Effect Will Not Go Away, 1975; MS138.001.001.00015; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    Behaviorism; Learning; Artificial intelligence; Skinner, B. F.; Popper, Karl R. (Karl Raimund), 1902-1994
  - Brain Writing and Mind Reading, 1975; MS138.001.001.00016; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - Review of Behavior Control: Freedom and Morality (an Open University film), by G. Warnock and B. F. Skinner, 1975; MS138.001.001.00017; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    Behaviorism; Determinism; Intentionality; Skinner, B. F.
  - Are Dreams Experiences?, 1976; MS138.001.001.00018; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    Dreams; Experience; Memory; Consciousness
    - Son Experiencias Los Sueños? [Spanish Translation of Are Dreams Experiences?], 1984; MS138.001.001.00018.00003; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - Conditions of Personhood, 1976 -- 2003; MS138.001.001.00019; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - Conditions of Personhood, 1976; MS138.001.001.00019.00001; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
      Self; Personal identity; Conciousness; Intentionality; Subjectivity
    - Bedingungen der Personalität [German translation of Conditions of Personhood], 1981; MS138.001.001.00019.00003; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    - Bedingungen der Personalität [German translation of Conditions of Personhood], 1983; MS138.001.001.00019.00004; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    - УСЛОВИЯ ЛИЧНОСТНОГО [Russian translation of Conditions of Personhood], 2000; MS138.001.001.00019.00005; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    - УСЛОВИЯ ЛИЧНОСТНОГО [Russian translation of Conditions of Personhood], 2003; MS138.001.001.00019.00006; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - Critical Notice of J. Fodor, The Language of Thought, 1977; MS138.001.001.00020; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - Review of Sentience by Wallace Matson, 1977; MS138.001.001.00021; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - Review of The Philosophy of Mind, edited by Jonathan Glover, 1977; MS138.001.001.00022; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    Book Reviews
  - Brainstorms: Philosophical Essays on Mind and Psychology, 1982 -- 1999; MS138.001.001.00023; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - Where am I?, 1982; MS138.001.001.00023.00002; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box Small Map Case 2 Drawer 5)
    - On Giving Libertarians What They Say They Want, 1995; MS138.001.001.00023.00003; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    - Onde Estou Eu? [Portuguese translation of Where am I?], 1996; MS138.001.001.00023.00004; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    - Gdzie jestem? [Polish translation of Where am I?], 1996; MS138.001.001.00023.00005; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - Brainstorms: Ensaiso Filosóficos sobre a mente e a psicologia [Portugese translation of Brainstorms: Philosophical Essays on Mind and Psychology], 1999; MS138.001.001.00023.00006; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box data_value_missing_ca701fe8d78187953f592b0c499a65b9)
  - Toward a Cognitive Theory of Consciousness, 1978; MS138.001.001.00024; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    Consciousness; Cognitive psychology; Phenomenology
  - Why You Can't Make a Computer that Feels Pain, 1978; MS138.001.001.00025; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    Artificial intelligence; Pain- Philosophy
  - Current Issues in the Philosophy of Mind, 1978 -- 1981; MS138.001.001.00026; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - Current Issues in the Philosophy of Mind, 1978; MS138.001.001.00026.00001; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
      Philosophy of mind; Ordinary-language philosophy; Conceptual analysis; Mind-brain identity theory; Functionalism; Qualia; Intentionality; Meaning (philosophy)
    - Perspectivas Actuales en la Filosofia de la Mente [Spanish translation of Current Issues in the Philosophy of Mind], 1981; MS138.001.001.00026.00003; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - Requisition for a Pexgo, 1978; MS138.001.001.00027; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    Behaviorism; Cognitive psychology; Intentional explanation; Artificial intelligence
  - Why Not the Whole Iguana?, 1978; MS138.001.001.00028; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    Computational modeling; Modularity (psychology); Artificial intelligence
  - Co-opting Holograms, 1978; MS138.001.001.00029; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - What's the Difference: Some Riddles, 1978; MS138.001.001.00030; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - Beliefs about Beliefs, 1978; MS138.001.001.00031; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - Review of Artificial Intelligence and Natural Man, by Margaret Boden, 1978; MS138.001.001.00032; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - The Philosophical Lexicon, 7th ed., 1978; MS138.001.001.00033; Dennett, Daniel C.; Lambert, Karel (Box 1)
    Philosophy- Dictionaries; Philosophy- Humor
  - On the Absence of Phenomenology, 1979; MS138.001.001.00034; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - The Onus Re Experiences: A Reply to Emmett, 1979; MS138.001.001.00035; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    Dreams; Experience; Memory; Conciousness; Lucid Dreams
  - Review of Intentionality: A Study of Mental Acts, by Richard E. Aquila and Imagining: A Phenomenological Analysis, by Edward S. Casey., 1979; MS138.001.001.00036; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - Review of The Self and its Brain: An Arguement for Interactionism, by Karl Popper and John Eccles, 1979; MS138.001.001.00037; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    Cognitive science; Neuroscience; Eccles, John C. (John Carew), 1903-1997; Popper, Karl R. (Karl Raimund), 1902-1994
  - Breeding Cognitive Strategies, 1979; MS138.001.001.00038; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    Eidetic imagery; Phenomenology
  - Artificial Intelligence as Philosophy and as Psychology, 1979; MS138.001.001.00039; Dennett, Daniel C.
    PLACEHOLDER RECORD.
  - Passing the Buck to Biology, 1980; MS138.001.001.00040; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    Universal grammar; Innateness hypothesis (linguistics); Chomsky, Noam
  - The Milk of Human Intentionality, 1980; MS138.001.001.00041; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    Intentionality
  - Reply to Professor Stich, 1980; MS138.001.001.00042; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    Intentionality; Artificial intelligence; Evolutionary biology; Rationality; Pain- Philosophy; Stich, Stephen P.
  - The Mind's I: Fantasies and Reflections on Self and Soul, 1981; MS138.001.001.00043; Dennett, Daniel C.; Hofstadter, Douglas R.
  - True Believers: the Intentional Strategy and Why it Works, 1981 -- 2014; MS138.001.001.00044; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - True Believers: the Intentional Strategy and Why it Works, 1981; MS138.001.001.00044.00001; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    - Intencionalidade [Portuguese translation of True Believers: the Intentional Strategy and Why it Works], 1991; MS138.001.001.00044.00002; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    - Naprawdę przekonani: strategia intencjonalna i dlaczego ona dziala [Polish translation of True Believers: the Intentional Strategy and Why it Works], 2003; MS138.001.001.00044.00003; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    - Georgian translation of True Believers, 2014; MS138.001.001.00044.00004; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - Wondering Where the Yellow Went, 1981; MS138.001.001.00045; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - Making Sense of Ourselves, 1981; MS138.001.001.00046; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - Three Kinds of Intentional Physchology, 1981; MS138.001.001.00047; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    Intentionality; Psychology - Philosophy; Rationality; Evolutionary biology; Functionalism; Ryle, Gilbert, 1900-1976
  - Beyond Belief, 1982; MS138.001.001.00048; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - Philosophy According to Nozick, 1982; MS138.001.001.00049; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - Grey Matter and Mind, 1982; MS138.001.001.00050; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box Small Map Case 2 Drawer 5)
  - Notes on Prosthetic Imagination, 1982 -- 2005; MS138.001.001.00051; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - Notes on Prosthetic Imagination, 1982; MS138.001.001.00051.00001; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box Small Map Case 2 Drawer 5)
    - Notes on Prosthetic Imagination, 2005; MS138.001.001.00051.00002; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - The Myth of the Computer: An Exchange, 1982; MS138.001.001.00052; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box Small Map Case 2 Drawer 5)
    The Mind's I: fantasies and relections on self and soul; Intentionality; Machine learning; Artificial intelligence; Searle, John R.; Hofstadter, Douglas R., 1945-
  - The Well-Furnished Mind: A Review of Mind in Science, by Richard Gregory, 1982; MS138.001.001.00053; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    Mind in science: a history of explanations in psychology and physics; Psychology; Philosophy; Gregory R. L. (Richard Langton)
  - Why We Think What We Do about Why We Think What We Do: Discussion on Goodman's On Thoughts without Words, 1982; MS138.001.001.00054; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    Introspection; A priori; Goodman, Nelson; Locke, John, 1632-1704; Ryle, Gilbert, 1900-1976
  - Correspondent's Report: Recent Work in Philosophy of Interest to AI, 1982; MS138.001.001.00055; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - How to Study Consciousness Empirically: or Nothing Comes to Mind, 1982; MS138.001.001.00056; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    Conciousness; Phenomenology; Heterophenomenology; Introspection; Artificial intelligence
  - Comments on Rorty, 1982; MS138.001.001.00057; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    A priori; Nuturalism; Meaning (philosophy); Rorty, Richard
  - The Imagination Extenders, 1982; MS138.001.001.00058; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - Review of On Thinking, by Gilbert Ryle, 1982; MS138.001.001.00059; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - Styles of Mental Representation, 1982; MS138.001.001.00060; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    Cognition; Research; Methodology; Cognitive psychology; Intentionality; Representation, Symbolic; Gregory R. L. (Richard Langton); Ryle, Gilbert, 1900-1976
  - Artificial Intelligence and the Strategies of Psychological Investigation: An Interview with Daniel C. Dennett), 1983; MS138.001.001.00061; Miller, Jonathan
    - Artificial Intelligence and the Strategies of Psychological Investigation: An Interview with Daniel C. Dennett), 1983; MS138.001.001.00061.00001; Miller, Jonathan (Box 1)
    - States of Mind: Conversations with Psychological Investigators, 1983; MS138.001.001.00061.00003; Miller, Jonathan (Box data_value_missing_ca701fe8d78187953f592b0c499a65b9)
  - Exploring the Labyrinth of the Mind, 1983; MS138.001.001.00062; Gleick, James (Box Small Map Case 2 Drawer 5)
    This article profiles Douglas Hofstadter and mention's Daniel C. Dennett.
  - Intentional Systems in Cognitive Ethology: the 'Panglossian Paradigm' Defended, 1983; MS138.001.001.00063; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - When do Representations Explain?, 1983; MS138.001.001.00064; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - Formulating Human Purposes: Meta-Engineering Computers for People, 1984; MS138.001.001.00065; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - Ellenbogenfreiheit: Die erstrebenswerten formen freiem willens [German translation of Elbow Room: The Varieties of Free Will Worth Wanting], 1994; MS138.001.001.00066; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box data_value_missing_ca701fe8d78187953f592b0c499a65b9)
  - Cognitive Wheels: The Frame Problem of AI, 1984 -- 1994; MS138.001.001.00067; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - Cognitive Wheels: The Frame Problem of AI, 1984; MS138.001.001.00067.00001; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
      Artificial intelligence; Frame problem; Induction; Non-monotonic inference; Paired-association learning
    - Las Ruedas de Conocimiento: El Problema Estructural de La IA [Spanish translation of Cognitive Wheels: The Frame Problem of AI], 1994; MS138.001.001.00067.00003; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - Wishful Thinking, 1984; MS138.001.001.00068; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - Foreword to Language, Thought and Other Biological Categories, by Ruth G. Millikan, 1984; MS138.001.001.00069; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - Carving the Mind at Its Joints: A Review of The Modularity of Mind: An Essay on Faculty Psychology, by Jerry A. Fodor, 1984; MS138.001.001.00070; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    Modularity (psychology); Cognitive psychology; Fodor, Jerry A.
  - Correspondent's Report: Recent Work in Philosophy II, 1984; MS138.001.001.00071; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - The Role of the Computer Metaphor in Understanding the Mind, 1984; MS138.001.001.00072; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - I Could Not Have Done Otherwise So What?, 1984 -- 1997; MS138.001.001.00073; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - I Could Not Have Done Otherwise So What?, 1984-10; MS138.001.001.00073.00001; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
      Free will and determinism
    - No podría haber actuado de otro modo, ¿y que? [Portuguese translation of I Could Not Have Done Otherwise So What?, 1997; MS138.001.001.00073.00002; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - Computer Models and the Mind: A View from the East Pole, 1984 -- 1986; MS138.001.001.00074; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - The Logical Geography of Computational Approaches: A View from the East Pole, 1986; MS138.001.001.00074.00001; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box Small Map Case 2 Drawer 5)
      Computational modeling; Cognitive science
    - Computer Models and the Mind: A View from the East Pole, 1984-12-14; MS138.001.001.00074.00002; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box Small Map Case 2 Drawer 5)
      This is a condensed version of "The Logical Geography of Computational Approaches: a View from the East Pole". This article was originally published in the Times Literary Supplement. Permission has been granted to reproduce the piece on the Tufts Digital Library.
  - Thinking about Thinking: the Mind as Virtual Machine, 1984; MS138.001.001.00075; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - Music of the Hemispheres: A Review of The Social Brain, by Michael S. Gazzaniga, 1985; MS138.001.001.00076; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - Can Machines Think?, 1985; MS138.001.001.00077; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - Can Machines Think?, 1985; MS138.001.001.00077.00001; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    - Kunnen machines denken? [Dutch translation of Can Machines Think?], 1985; MS138.001.001.00077.00002; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - When Does the Intentional Stance Work?", 1985; MS138.001.001.00078; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - Why Believe in Belief?: A Review of From Folk Psychology to Cognitive Science: The Case Against Belief, by Stephen Stich, 1985; MS138.001.001.00079; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    Belief; Intentionality; Psychology - Philosophy; Cognitive science; Stich, Stephen P.
  - Phenomenology and Speech Disposition, 1985; MS138.001.001.00080; Cam, Phillip (Box 1)
  - Commentary in Artificial Intelligence - Where Are We?, 1985; MS138.001.001.00081; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - Review of Vehicles: Experiments in Synthetic Psychology, by Valentino Braitenberg, 1986; MS138.001.001.00082; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - Julian Jaynes's Software Archeology, 1986; MS138.001.001.00083; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - The Imagination Extenders, 1986; MS138.001.001.00084; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - Engineering's Baby, 1986; MS138.001.001.00085; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - Who May I Say is Calling?, 1986; MS138.001.001.00086; Dennett, Daniel C.; Atkins, Kathleen A. (Box 1)
  - Philosophy as Mathematics or as Anthropology, 1986; MS138.001.001.00087; Dennett, Daniel C.
    Metaphilosophy; Nuturalism; A priori
  - Is there an Autonomous 'Knowledge Level'?, 1986; MS138.001.001.00088; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    Intentionality; Holism-semantics; Intentional explanation; Newell, Allen
  - Information, Technology, and the Virtues of Ignorance, 1986; MS138.001.001.00089; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - The Self as the Center of Narrative Gravity, 1986 -- 1992; MS138.001.001.00090; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - Selvet som fortӕllingens tyngdepunkt [Danish translation of The Self as the Center of Narrative Gravity], 1986; MS138.001.001.00090.00001; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    - The Self as the Center of Narrative Gravity, 1992; MS138.001.001.00090.00002; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - Moral Thinking Under Time Pressure, 1986; MS138.001.001.00091; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - Postscript to Evolution, Error and Intentionality, 1995; MS138.001.001.00092; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Skinner Placed: A Commentary on Place's 'Skinner Re-Skinned', 1987; MS138.001.001.00093; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - Consciousness, 1987; MS138.001.001.00094; Dennett, Daniel C.; Haugeland, John, 1945-2010 (Box 1)
  - Intentionality, 1987; MS138.001.001.00095; Dennett, Daniel C.; Haugeland, John, 1945-2010 (Box 1)
  - Comments on Pylyshyn, Computers, Knowledge, and the Human Mind, 1987; MS138.001.001.00096; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - Eliminate the Middletoad!, 1987-09; MS138.001.001.00097; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    Cognitive science
  - Commentary on Cam, 1987; MS138.001.001.00098; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - The Philosophical Lexicon, 8th Edition, 1987; MS138.001.001.00099; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - When Philosophers Encounter Artificial Intelligence, 1988; MS138.001.001.00100; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - The Moral First Aid Manual, 1988; MS138.001.001.00101; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    Ethics; Metaethics; Applied ethics; Decision making; Mill, J.S. (John Stuart), 1806-1873
  - Out of the Armchair and Into the Field, 1988; MS138.001.001.00102; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    Language; Vervet Monkey; Intentionality; Animal intelligence
  - Quining Qualia, 1988 -- 2006; MS138.001.001.00103; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - Quining Qualia, 1988; MS138.001.001.00103.00001; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    - Kvaalide kvainimine (part I) [Estonian translation of Quining Qualia], 1997; MS138.001.001.00103.00002; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    - Kvaalide kvainimine (part II) [Estonian translation of Quining Qualia], 1998; MS138.001.001.00103.00003; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    - Discreditând qualia [Romanian translation of Quining Qualia], 2002; MS138.001.001.00103.00004; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    - Quinear Los Qualia [Spanish translation of Quining Qualia], 2003; MS138.001.001.00103.00005; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)